The night he came home!
Halloween is a horror, thriller film directed by John Carpenter.
Fifteen years after murdering his sister on Halloween Night 1963, Michael Myers escapes from a
mental hospital and returns to the small town of Haddonfield, Illinois to kill again.
Loomis, played by Donald Pleasence.
Laurie, played by Jamie Lee Curtis.
Annie, played by Nancy Kyes.
Lynda, played by P. J. Soles.
Brackett, played by Charles Cyphers.
Lindsey, played by Kyle Richards.
Halloween is a 1978 American independent slasher film directed and scored by
John Carpenter, who co-wrote it with producer Debra Hill.
It stars Donald Pleasence, Jamie Lee Curtis (in her film debut), P.
Soles, and Nancy Loomis.
Set in the fictional Illinois town of Haddonfield, the film follows escaped mental patient Michael Myers, who was committed to a mental institution for murdering his teenage
sister on Halloween; 15 years later, he returns to Haddonfield, where he stalks teenage babysitter Laurie Strode and her friends while his psychiatrist Dr.
Samuel Loomis pursues him.
The film was shot in Southern California, produced by Compass
International Pictures, and Falcon International Productions.
The film was released by Compass International  and Aquarius Releasing in October and grossed $70 million (equivalent to $337 million in 2024)
on a budget of $300,000 (equivalent to $1,446,300 in 2024), becoming one of the most profitable independent films of all time.
Primarily praised for Carpenter's direction and score, many critics credit the film as pioneering the slasher genre,
alongside other films such as Psycho (1960), The Texas Chain Saw Massacre and Black Christmas (both 1974).
It is considered one of the greatest and most
influential horror films ever made.
In 2006, it was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
Halloween spawned a film franchise comprising 13 films, with some sequels narratively diverging entirely from previous
installments, as well as a novelization, video game, board game, and comic book series have also been based on the film.
The film explores themes of mask, police, halloween, babysitter, marijuana.
The tone is dark and intense.